<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Anthony&#39;s Blogs</title>
    <link>https://anthony-tan.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Anthony&#39;s Blogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 17:01:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://anthony-tan.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fisher Linear Discriminant(LDA)</title>
      <link>https://anthony-tan.com/Fisher-Linear-Discriminant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 17:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anthony-tan.com/Fisher-Linear-Discriminant/</guid>
      <description>Preliminaries linear algebra   inner multiplication projection  Idea of Fisher linear discriminant1 ‘Least-square method’ in classification can only deal with a small set of tasks. That is because it was designed for the regression task. Then we come to the famous Fisher linear discriminant. This method is also discriminative for it gives directly the class to which the input \(\mathbf{x}\) belongs. Assuming that the linear function
\[ y=\mathbf{w}^T\mathbf{x}+w_0\tag{1} \]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discriminant Functions and Decision Boundary</title>
      <link>https://anthony-tan.com/Discriminant-Functions-and-Decision-Boundary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 16:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anthony-tan.com/Discriminant-Functions-and-Decision-Boundary/</guid>
      <description>Preliminaries convex definition linear algebra   vector length vector direction  Discriminant Function in Classification The discriminant function or discriminant model is on the other side of the generative model. And we, here, have a look at the behavior of the discriminant function in linear classification.1
In the post ‘Least Squares Classification’, we have seen, in a linear classification task, the decision boundary is a line or hyperplane by which we separate two classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Least Squares in Classification</title>
      <link>https://anthony-tan.com/Least-Squares-in-Classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 12:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anthony-tan.com/Least-Squares-in-Classification/</guid>
      <description>Preliminaries A Simple Linear Regression Least Squares Estimation From Linear Regression to Linear Classification pseudo-inverse  Least Squares for Classification1 Least-squares for linear regression had been talked about in ‘Simple Linear Regression’. And in this post, we want to find out whether this powerful algorithm can be used in classification.
Recalling the distinction between the properties of classification and regression, two points need to be emphasized again(‘From Linear Regression to Linear Classification’):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Linear Regression to Linear Classification</title>
      <link>https://anthony-tan.com/From-Linear-Regression-to-Linear-Classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 11:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anthony-tan.com/From-Linear-Regression-to-Linear-Classification/</guid>
      <description>Preliminaries An Introduction to Linear Regression A Simple Linear Regression Bayesian theorem Feature extraction  Recall Linear Regression The goal of a regression problem is to find out a function or hypothesis that given an input \(\mathbf{x}\), it can make a prediction \(\hat{y}\) to estimate the target. Both the target \(y\) and prediction \(\hat{y}\) here are continuous. They have the properties of numbers1:
 Consider 3 inputs \(\mathbf{x}_1\), \(\mathbf{x}_2\) and \(\mathbf{x}_3\) and their coresponding targets are \(y_1=0\), \(y_2=1\) and \(y_3=2\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polynomial Regression and Features-Extension of Linear Regression</title>
      <link>https://anthony-tan.com/Polynomial-Regression-and-Features-Extension-of-Linear-Regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 22:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anthony-tan.com/Polynomial-Regression-and-Features-Extension-of-Linear-Regression/</guid>
      <description>Priliminaries A Simple Linear Regression Least Squares Estimation  Extending Linear Regression with Features1 The original linear regression is in the form:
\[ \begin{aligned} y(\mathbf{x})&amp;amp;= b + \mathbf{w}^T \mathbf{x}\\ &amp;amp;=w_01 + w_1x_1+ w_2x_2+\cdots + w_{m+1}x_{m+1} \end{aligned}\tag{1} \]
where the input vector \(\mathbf{x}\) and parameter \(\mathbf{w}\) are \(m\)-dimension vectors whose first components are \(1\) and bias \(w_0=b\) respectively. This equation is linear for both the input vector and parameter vector. Then an idea come to us, if we set \(x_i=\phi_i(\mathbf{x})\) then equation (1) convert to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximum Likelihood Estimation</title>
      <link>https://anthony-tan.com/Maximum-Likelihood-Estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anthony-tan.com/Maximum-Likelihood-Estimation/</guid>
      <description>Priliminaries A Simple Linear Regression Least Squares Estimation linear algebra  Square Loss Function for Regression1 For any input \(\mathbf{x}\), our goal in a regression task is to give a prediction \(\hat{y}=f(\mathbf{x})\) to approximate target \(t\) where the function \(f(\cdot)\) is the chosen hypothesis or model as mentioned in the post https://anthony-tan.com/A-Simple-Linear-Regression/.
The difference between \(t\) and \(\hat{y}\) can be called ‘error’ or more precisely ‘loss’. Because in an approximation task, ‘error’ occurs by chance and always exists, and ‘loss’ is a good word to represent the difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Least Squares Estimation</title>
      <link>https://anthony-tan.com/Least-Squares-Estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 11:33:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anthony-tan.com/Least-Squares-Estimation/</guid>
      <description>Priliminaries A Simple Linear Regression the column space  Another Example of Linear Regression 1 In the blog A Simple Linear Regression, squares of the difference between the output of a predictor and the target were used as a loss function in a regression problem. And it could be also written as:
\[ \ell(\hat{\mathbf{y}}_i,\mathbf{y}_i)=(\hat{\mathbf{y}}_i-\mathbf{y}_i)^T(\hat{\mathbf{y}}_i-\mathbf{y}_i) \tag{1} \]
The linear regression model in a matrix form is:
\[ y=\mathbf{w}^T\mathbf{x}+\mathbf{b}\tag{2} \]
What we do in this post is analyze the least-squares methods from two different viewpoints</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Linear Regression</title>
      <link>https://anthony-tan.com/A-Simple-Linear-Regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 20:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anthony-tan.com/A-Simple-Linear-Regression/</guid>
      <description>Preliminaries Linear Algebra(the concepts of space, vector) Calculus An Introduction to Linear Regression  Notations of Linear Regression1 We have already created a simple linear model in the post “An Introduction to Linear Regression”. According to the definition of linearity, we can develop the simplest linear regression model:
\[ Y\sim w_1X+w_0\tag{1} \]
where the symbol \(\sim\) is read as “is approximately modeled as”. Equation (1) can also be described as “regressing \(Y\) on \(X\)(or \(Y\) onto \(X\))”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Linear Regression</title>
      <link>https://anthony-tan.com/An-Introduction-to-Linear-Regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 18:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anthony-tan.com/An-Introduction-to-Linear-Regression/</guid>
      <description>Preliminariess Linear Algebra(the concepts of space, vector) Calculus  What is Linear Regression Linear regression is a basic idea in statistical and machine learning based on the linear combination. And it was usually used to predict some responses to some inputs(predictors).
Machine Learning and Statistical Learning Machine learning and statistical learning are similar but have some distinctions. In machine learning, models, regression models, or classification models, are used to predict the outputs of the new incoming inputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://anthony-tan.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anthony-tan.com/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Anthony Tan(谭升). I am now living in Shenzhen, China. I&amp;rsquo;m a full-time computer vision algorithm engineer and a part-time individual reinforcement learning researcher. I have had a great interest in artificial intelligence since I watched the movie &amp;ldquo;Iron man&amp;rdquo; when I was a middle school student. And to get deeper into these subjects, I&amp;rsquo;d like to apply for a Ph.D. project on reinforcement learning in the following years.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
