<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Learning on Anthony&#39;s Blogs</title>
    <link>https://anthony-tan.com/deep_learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deep Learning on Anthony&#39;s Blogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://anthony-tan.com/deep_learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Neuron Model and Network Architecture</title>
      <link>https://anthony-tan.com/deep_learning/neuron-model-and-network-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 10:54:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anthony-tan.com/deep_learning/neuron-model-and-network-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Preliminaries  linear classifier An Introduction to Neural Networks   Theory and Notation1 We are not able to build any artificial cells up to now. It seems impossible to build a neuron network through biological materials manually, either. To investigate the ability of neurons we have built mathematical models of the neuron. These models have been assigned a number of neuron-like properties. However, there must be a balance between the number of properties contained by the mathemetical models and the current computational abilities of the machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://anthony-tan.com/An-Introduction-to-Neural-Networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 19:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anthony-tan.com/An-Introduction-to-Neural-Networks/</guid>
      <description>Preliminaries Nothing  Neural Networks1 Neural Networks are a model of our brain that is built with neurons and is considered the source of intelligence. There are almost \(10^{11}\) neurons in the human brain and \(10^4\) connections of each neuron to other neurons. Some of these brilliant structures were given when we were born. Some other structures could be established by experience, and this progress is called learning. Learning is also considered as the establishment or modification of the connections between neurons.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
